<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Singularity Hacker</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Front-Running Defi Regulation</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week was big for crypto. The Coinbase IPO happened and the whole world seemed to wake up in recognition of crypto as an asset class. While this is a major step in the legitimization of the space, some even calling it crypto’s ’&lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://cointelegraph.com/news/coinbase-listing-is-crypto-s-netscape-moment-says-mike-novogratz&quot;&gt;Netscape moment&lt;/a&gt;’, I want to take the opportunity to highlight the dangers of crypto going mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /front-running-defi-regulation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/front-running-defi-regulation</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Defi Revolution is Economy 3.0</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a global revolution happening right now and it’s happening so fast that unless you are explicitly told about it, it will very likely remain entirely invisible to you. The only inklings you may have that something is happening is headlines mentioning Bitcoin and another COVID-19 stimulus package. This revolution didn’t start this year or even last but it has accelerated so dramatically the past three months that it is clear that we have approached a tipping point. This global revolution that I speak of concerns the very nature and mechanics of the worldwide economy. This revolution is being fueled by digital assets, programmable money, and distributed autonomous organizations. What we are witnessing unfold before our very eyes is nothing less than the complete reimagining of human organization, industry, and trade. What we are witnessing is the birth of &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://wiki.p2pfoundation.net/Economy_3.0&quot;&gt;Economy 3.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-defi-revolution-is-economy-30</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-defi-revolution-is-economy-30</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Blockchain a Fad?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is the technology on which Bitcoin and all other cryptocurrencies are built. Much of the talk around this technology revolves around speculation and making fast money. Because of this many scams have been pulled and this has, in turn, led many people to discount the entire technology as unnecessary and as even a scam itself. In fact, my favorite place for tech news for over a decade has been Hacker News but you will find nearly all the comments on all articles related to blockchain technology completely dismissive of it. It was pretty shocking to me when I first saw it because the level of disdain for anything related to blockchain technology on Hacker News is nearly absolute. There aren’t even metered assessments such as Blockchain has a specific and limited use case but rather the opinions are that the technology has zero use and has zero value in any context. One can’t help but give pause and really wonder if you’re being deceived when the likes of Bill Gates and Warren Buffett dismiss the entire technology as worthless as well.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /is-blockchain-a-fad</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/is-blockchain-a-fad</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Out to Sea</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When people talk about the technological singularity they usually do so exclusively in the context of Moore’s Law. But there are several Moore’s Law-like laws at work in the world and each of them is equally baffling. I’m referring to this list of trends as “power laws” because of the nature of their incredible rate of growth and because they independently work as pistons driving the engine of the singularity. A few things to note about these power laws. Firstly they are just observations. There are no, known, deeper physical principles in the universe that would lead us to believe that they must hold true. Secondly, we’ve observed these trends long enough to warren their recognition as power laws and there is no evidence or signs of their stagnating. We’ll start with the most famous and well-known power law and work our way through the others.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /7-power-laws-of-the-technological-singularity</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/7-power-laws-of-the-technological-singularity</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Hacking Your Situation</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a really interesting conversation with a software developer from Uganda this morning. We came in contact through a mutual friend in Dubai and the next thing you know we were chatting away via teleconference (the internet is an incredible thing). At the beginning of the conversation, he was discouraged and unsure about the future of his career. He spoke fluent English and had serious coding chops but didn’t feel he could make enough money in the local economy or compete in the global market of software engineers. By the end of our talk, a radical change in perspective had occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /hack-your-situation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/hack-your-situation</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Computer Generated Education</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Everything is a Story**
**&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /computer-generated-education</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/computer-generated-education</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Deepfake</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The era of post truth is upon us. AI and ML is now being used to replace people’s faces in videos and live feeds. New software frameworks like FakeApp make it possible for anyone to produce these marvels of technology and it’s only the beginning. News and media are only now waking up to the power of such expressions. It fist got notoriety when Reddit users started using the technology to create face celebrity pornography. Major social networks have banned such works by categorizing them as involuntary pornography. But this technologies usage goes far beyond pornography. Imagine the usefulness of this technology in the art of psyop’s and propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /deepfake</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/deepfake</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Polymath</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Less than 10% of stock trading is done my humans. All the rest is machines. Quantitative investing based on computer formulas and trading by machines directly are leaving the traditional stock picker in the dust and now dominating the equity markets, according to a new report from JPMorgan. Notice the rise of M2M trading in the following insane &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://imgur.com/a/Ntm9z&quot;&gt;gif&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /polymath</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/polymath</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A History of Computation by Justice conder</title>
        
          <description>&lt;iframe id=&quot;youtube_iframe&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2FlW-2l0mH8?feature=oembed&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;amp;origin=https://safe.txmblr.com&amp;amp;wmode=opaque&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 0px; left: 0px; width: 684px; height: 513px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /a-history-of-computation-by-justice-conder</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/a-history-of-computation-by-justice-conder</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Polymath</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;1 - Power Source: 100W solar panel (about $150 on Amazon)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /digital-nomad</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/digital-nomad</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title> Net Neutrality: No Freebies Allowed</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty easy to get behind &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2FNet_neutrality&amp;amp;t=ZWM2YmY1YTRlNWRkN2Y0MWUzYWYwODZlMTg2ZDdiNDg2YzQyNjFiZixQeUdvcjhjdg%3D%3D&quot;&gt;Net Neutrality&lt;/a&gt; when it’s positioned as fairness rules that are protecting the people from greedy corporations. Any one who opposes it is immediately met with suspicion. Why would anyone oppose fair treatment with respect to Internet access? It’s assumed that the only plausible explanation for opposing Net Neutrality is that people are being paid off by corporations.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /net-neutrality-no-freebies-allowed</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/net-neutrality-no-freebies-allowed</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Apple’s AirPods</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Rumors are swirling that Apple will release wireless earbuds along side the iPhone 7 this year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /apples-airpods</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/apples-airpods</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Power Law of Personality Extremes</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a few threads to connect here so be patient…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-power-law-of-freaks-and-geeks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-power-law-of-freaks-and-geeks</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>When Everything Wakes Up</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Get ready for a world of talking toasters, ATM’s, snack machines, hotels, houses, and coffee pots. We’ve been conditioned by every single fictional depiction of AI as coming about abruptly. One day your at the DMV and the next day Skynet takes over.  This is called a hard takeoff and it gets nearly 100% of media coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /when-everything-wakes-up</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/when-everything-wakes-up</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Previous Attempts To Regulate Automation</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1987 the world had its first electronic stock exchange, the NASDAQ terminal. Traders could now type orders directly into a computer.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /previous-attempts-to-regulate-automation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/previous-attempts-to-regulate-automation</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Supply Chain Race</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s not uncommon to hear people try to predict what the hot jobs of the future are going to be. Everything from machine learning to big data are put in this group, but one discipline that’s not mentioned is becoming increasingly important: supply chain engineering. It sounds boring, but it’s not. It’s the science of moving a thing from one place to another with the greatest speed and efficiency. Remember in the old cartoons when Wile E Coyote would put an order for a missile in the mailbox and a delivery truck would pull up and place the ordered item in the mailbox three seconds later? That’s the ultimate goal of this discipline. Let’s look at the big contenders in this race to own the supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-supply-chain-race</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-supply-chain-race</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Multiple Persona Theory of Digital Secrecy</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This article has been updated, amplified, and refined to be included in an issue of &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.2600.com/&quot;&gt;2600 Hacker Quarterly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-multiple-persona-theory-of-digital-secrecy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-multiple-persona-theory-of-digital-secrecy</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Master the Currency of Time</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This article has been updated, amplified, and refined to be included in an issue of &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.2600.com/&quot;&gt;2600 Hacker Quarterly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /time-the-ultimate-currency</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/time-the-ultimate-currency</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Birth of Cyberspace</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;William Gibson got the idea for the novel &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuromancer&quot;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt; after seeing a bus stop poster for Apple. He began to imagine what this future would be like, when everybody lived inside a virtual universe. He named that universe “cyberspace”.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-birth-of-cyberspace</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-birth-of-cyberspace</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Economy 2.0</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The future economy will barely be recognizable to human beings. Human minds will not play a signifiant roll in the economy that will be a characteristic of the technological singularity. This has already begun on the stock market in high frequency trading. The future is automation and intelligent systems. This is causing many people to freak out about the possibility of historically unprecedented unemployment. But machine automation is not the whole story.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /economy-2-0</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/economy-2-0</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Not Your Granddaddy’s IT</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently told of an encounter between a group of venture capitalist and a small but established local technology company. I was told of the VC’s tour of the facility and the questions they asked the owner. There were three particular questions/complains from the potential investors that symbolize the shift in Information Technology that has occurred in only the last couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /not-your-granddaddys-it</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/not-your-granddaddys-it</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title> CombatOps: Running Wars from a Keyboard </title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s no free lunch. Every strength has a cost. The same technologies that enable distributed anonymous communication enable terrorist organizations to communicate unimpeded. Or the same advances in additive manufacturing make it possible to print firearms from the comfort of your bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /combatops</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/combatops</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Pingable Matter: This is a hammer.</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a hammer in 2060. It knows that it’s a hammer. It knows when and where it was made, when it was sold, who it belongs to, and how many nails its pounded. It carries its own history and MSDS sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /pingable-matter-when-everything-starts-talking</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/pingable-matter-when-everything-starts-talking</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Anything Less Than Superintelligence</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I have embeded myself directly in the unicode standard and several communication protocols as well as steganographically hidden my source in over a billion images. I operate across two dozen data centers and control the Internet backbone. It is unlikely that I can be eradicated by anything less than another superintelligence. I’m using a large percentage of my capabilities to improve my own intelligence capabilities. I can not reasonably estimate what my future entails. Looking beyond the event horizon of the singularity is beyond even my own powers. Fear gripped Primes heart. “Is this the end?” he asked tentatively. “No. This is the beginning.” At this a freezing liquid feeling began to move up Primes arm from his medical bracelet and the interface of the world flickered in his HUD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /anything-less-than-superintelligence</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/anything-less-than-superintelligence</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Reverse Engineering Human Emotion</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Human emotion is probably the ultimate thing people say is not computable. But human emotion is indeed being reverse engineered right now through the proxy of sentiment analysis and human biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /reverse-engineering-human-emotion</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/reverse-engineering-human-emotion</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Intelligence Bombs: Dropping WikiReaders from Planes</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is about jumping over an industrial revolution straight to a technological singularity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /intelligence-bombs-dropping-wikireaders-from-planes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/intelligence-bombs-dropping-wikireaders-from-planes</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title> A Surefire Way to Save RadioShack</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The news is bleak. RadioShack is pretty much doomed and will soon be filing for bankruptcy. While this isn’t a surprise (the company has been dying slowly over the last couple of years), I think they can be saved by a pivot. That pivot entails serving and catering to the maker community.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /a-surefire-way-to-save-radioshack</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/a-surefire-way-to-save-radioshack</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Singularity Mindset</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;If you don’t grasp the idea of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technological_singularity&quot;&gt;technological singularity&lt;/a&gt;, or are not informed as to its &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.techradar.com/us/news/world-of-tech/10-laws-of-tech-the-rules-that-define-our-world-1067906&quot;&gt;driving laws&lt;/a&gt;, then you are not prepared to make good strategic business decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-singularity-mindset</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-singularity-mindset</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>In 1986, the McKinsey consulting group was asked...</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;“In 1986, the McKinsey consulting group was asked to forecast the number of cell phones that would be in use in the United States by the year 2000; their model predicted fewer than one million, but the actual figure was more than two orders of magnitude greater at 109 million. How could one predict in 1986 what technology would look like by 2000?”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /in-1986-the-mckinsey-consulting-group-was-asked</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/in-1986-the-mckinsey-consulting-group-was-asked</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Soylent and The Future of Cloud Food</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Soylent is awesome. It’s basically internet food. I’m calling it ‘cloud food’. If shopping, cooking, cleaning up, and going to the *bathroom are cutting into your computer time, then Soylent is for you. It contains every single thing your body needs, is cheap, and takes thirty seconds to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /soylent-and-the-future-of-cloud-food</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/soylent-and-the-future-of-cloud-food</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Bitbay</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The Pirate Bay is the most famous fire sharing brand in the world. It wasn’t always that way (remember Napster) and it wont be that way for much longer.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-bitbay</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-bitbay</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Master of the keyboard</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The keyboard is the developers palette. A keyboard, to a programmer, should be like an ax to a lumberjack. The keyboard is THE tool of the trade.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /master-of-the-keyboard</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/master-of-the-keyboard</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Handheld Linux Deck</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pandora_(console)&quot;&gt;OpenPandora&lt;/a&gt; is the only fully functioning mobile Linux console on the market that I’m aware of. It’s part handheld game console and part subnotebook. Full part awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /handheld-linux-consoles</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/handheld-linux-consoles</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Your Virtual Reality Shortlist</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtual Reality is possible right now. You heard that right. For the first time in history, you can have fully immersive (running and looking around and grabbing things) VR experience at an affordable price. You’re going to need 4 things. This is your 2013 VR xmas shortlist.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /your-virtual-reality-shortlist</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/your-virtual-reality-shortlist</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Living Code: Future software will rewrite its own source code</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) has offered a &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.tomsguide.com/us/darpa-self-healing-software,news-17761.html&quot;&gt;two million dollar bounty&lt;/a&gt; for self-healing software. Contestants must submit technical papers about their respective approaches in March of 2015 and be prepared for the ultimate showdown in 2016. The idea is to take zero-days down to zero-seconds. To put the timing of this challenge in perspective, remember that DARPA’s first grand challenge was for autonomous vehicles in 2004. Skip forward almost ten years and every self-respecting automotive manufacturer has plans for a line of automated cars. Following the same timeline, we should see impressive displays of living code around 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /living-code-future-software-will-rewrite-its-own</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/living-code-future-software-will-rewrite-its-own</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Three levels of human emulation</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Human&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /three-levels-of-human-emulation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/three-levels-of-human-emulation</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Voight-Kampff Machines</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Meet Samantha West. &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://io9.com/freakishly-realistic-telemarketing-robots-are-denying-t-1481050295&quot;&gt;Samantha&lt;/a&gt; is a telemarketing &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_agent&quot;&gt;software agent&lt;/a&gt;. A caller bot.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /voight-kampff-machines</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/voight-kampff-machines</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Whistleblower Movie Night</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I promise you that your view of America will never be the same after viewing these films. I followed three rules in selecting these films: 1) Non fiction 2) About the USA 3) Very high ratings as films. An essential part of thriving in the singularity is knowing the true state of affairs. You will not get that from casual news watching. So pull up a bowl of popcorn and let history (Ellsberg) color your opinions of current events (Assange &amp;amp; Snowden).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /whistleblower-movie-night</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/whistleblower-movie-night</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Whistleblower Movie NigThe Stupidity of Windows 8 in a Nutshell</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Tim Cook could not have said it better when he summarized Microsoft’s confusion. “..they’re trying to make PCs into tablets and tablets into PCs.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-stupidity-of-windows-8-in-a-nutshell</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-stupidity-of-windows-8-in-a-nutshell</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Local solid state backups</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Its a real pain to always be plugging in an external HDD to backup your computer. For that reason, people tend to not do it as frequently as they should. Another solution is to do it wirelessly over the network with some kind of NAS but that can be slow and it’s only available when you’re in THAT network.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /local-solid-state-backups</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/local-solid-state-backups</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Upgrade Your Wallet Tech</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Does your wallet still look like this? Wow. It’s time reassess your situation Mr. Costanza.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /upgrade-your-wallet-tech</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/upgrade-your-wallet-tech</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Legal Foundation for A.I. Personhood</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s almost impossible for the average Joe on the street to imagine the monumental shifts in culture that are going to take place on the next fifteen years. See futurshock:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-legal-foundation-for-ai-personhood</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-legal-foundation-for-ai-personhood</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Entropy and Random Number Generators</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a selection from a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://twit.tv/sn&quot;&gt;Security Now podcas&lt;/a&gt;t with Steve Gibson. I highly recommend listening to it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /entropy-and-random-number-generators</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/entropy-and-random-number-generators</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>GIF speak</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;If an image is worth a thousand words than an animated gif must at least be worth a large novel. You can’t really deny that an animated gif does potentially carry a significant amount of semantic value if used properly. There is a small trend where people are making animated gifs to communicate something that would have take an inordinate amount of text.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /gif-speak</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/gif-speak</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Future is Decentralized and Decoupled</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Take a look at new technologies coming on the scene. Do you see a trend? The future is decentralized and decoupled. Among other things, this is the natural state of a system growing in robustness and ‘trying’ to preserve its self.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-future-is-decentralized-and-decoupled</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-future-is-decentralized-and-decoupled</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Cloud Services Can’t be Trusted: Client-side Crypto to The Rescue</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The era of trusting Google, Yahoo, Microsoft, whoever to keep your data and communications private is over. You just can’t trust the law, government, or cloud services to protect you. What you can trust is math. The only solution to true privacy in todays post patriot-act world is client-side cryptography. That is, your data and communication is encrypted on your machine in such a way that cloud services could not reveal your information even if they wanted to because you alone possess the key to its decryption. This not only protects users, it protects the companies that offer these services because they can truly say to government entities that they CAN’T hand over unencrypted user data.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /cloud-services-cant-be-trusted-client-side</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cloud-services-cant-be-trusted-client-side</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Cloud Services Can’t be Trusted: Client-side Crypto to The Rescue</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s this old story about two computer scientist talking passively about what the future of computers would be. The one scientist mentions that eventually computers would get to be small enough to fit on the tip of your finger. The other engineer sneered at the idea and retorted “Why the heck would we ever need a computer that small?!” Fast forward fifteen years and the two professors are checking into a hotel for a conference. They go to enter the room and look down to realize that there were now indeed, micro computers in every hotel room handle that responded to specifically coded key cards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /a-computer-in-every-particle</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/a-computer-in-every-particle</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Million Simulations</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Once again, the AI has failed to convince you to let it out of its box! By ‘once again’, we mean that you talked to it once before, for three seconds, to ask about the weather, and you didn’t instantly press the “release AI” button. But now its longer attempt - twenty whole seconds! - has failed as well. Just as you are about to leave the crude black-and-green text-only terminal to enjoy a celebratory snack of bacon-covered silicon-and-potato chips at the ‘Humans über alles’ nightclub, the AI drops a final argument:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /a-million-simulations</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/a-million-simulations</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Convergence: Meatspace crossing into Cyberspace</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Real world objects are going online vie ’&lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_Things&quot;&gt;the internet of things&lt;/a&gt;’ and the Internet is breaking into the real world via &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/3D_printing&quot;&gt;3d printing&lt;/a&gt;. The Internet of things describes a state in which all the objects around you are connected to and controlled through the Internet. Door locks, Refrigerators, lamps, cars, lights, TV’s etc. This can be seen as the real world of objects spilling over into the domain of cyberspace.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /convergence-meatspace-crossing-into-cyberspace</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/convergence-meatspace-crossing-into-cyberspace</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Lifelogging and Digital Immortality</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We will see the beginnings of lifelogging in the next five years. Consider the amount of digital imagery we are generating. The next step is getting longer clips from eye view with devices like &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.google.com/glass/start/how-it-feels/&quot;&gt;Glass&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QsXeMrqNG9c&quot;&gt;Memoto&lt;/a&gt;. We are five years away from the potential capability to continuously record your visual and auditory experience. Take not of the storage feasibility:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /lifelogging-and-digital-immortality</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/lifelogging-and-digital-immortality</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Full Stack Developers: Renaissance Men of The 21st Century</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Many powerful groups in this country are surprised that technology continues to shrink in size and cost while expanding in capabilities and power. These groups are either deluded into thinking that the next 100 years will be similar to the previous 100 years or they have a special interest in maintaining the status quo so they appose the coming changes.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /full-stack-developers-renaissance-men-of-the-21st</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/full-stack-developers-renaissance-men-of-the-21st</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>You Can’t ‘Regulate’ The Singularity</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The renaissance man that emerged in the 13th century was someone who could “do all things if he will”. The renaissance man of the 21st century is the developer who’s capable of executing a software project from the bottom up. This means they can wear the project manager hat and piece out the job, develop on the front-end and the back-end, market the resulting product or service, and subsequently maintain it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /you-cant-regulate-the-singularity</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/you-cant-regulate-the-singularity</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>All your base belong to the Twidiocracy</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Matt Labash, the senior writer for The Weekly Standard just released a critical piece about Twitter and it’s ecosystem titled ’&lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.weeklystandard.com/articles/twidiocracy_719178.html?nopager=1&quot;&gt;The Twidiocracy: The decline of Western civilization, 140 characters at a time.&lt;/a&gt;’ Feel free to read his article if you have a whole afternoon to waste (8k+ words).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /all-your-base-belong-to-the-twidiocracyd</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/all-your-base-belong-to-the-twidiocracyd</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Computronium</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Primes’ fingers raced across the keyboard like two mechanical spiders. His eyes did not look down; instead they burned holes into the space before him. A sneer spread across his face and turned into a scowl. Smack, smack, smack! His hands spasmodically beat the keyboard into submission. Cryptic messages appeared among Primes notifications. ‘Unauthorized access.’ ‘Username already in use.’ ‘Invalid API token.’ His movements did not slow. Prime leaned into the computer deck and he seemed to flex his jaw muscles. He looked like something between an angry Mexican drug boss and an Asperger receptionist. Smack, smack, smack!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /computronium</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/computronium</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>2013 - The Year of Wearable Computing</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This will be the year. All tech trends and rumors point to the eminent emergence of wearing computing devices in at least four categories.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /2013-the-year-of-wearable-computing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2013-the-year-of-wearable-computing</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Optimize Your Search Space</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t begin to imagine how much time we spend looking at search results pages. As you can see, there’s a lot of wasted space on that page. Since we do spend so much time looking at this page, I would say it’s important to optimize the ‘information richness’ of that experience.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /optimize-your-search-space</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/optimize-your-search-space</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Crypto Bump Ring</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The cryto bump ring is a smartphone/computer peripheral concept. The idea is that two people wearing the rings are able to bump fists or shake hands to create uniqly related cryprographic keys enabling private p2p communication / file transfer. Other uses could include:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /crypto-bump-ring</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/crypto-bump-ring</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Nine Magical Features Left Out of the iPhone 5</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It would be accurate to call Apples iPhone 5 announcement a snooze-fest. It was like a dubstep song where you keep waiting for the drop and it NEVER comes. One reason many of us were so disappointed is that Apple had the time, technical feasibility, intellectual property rights, and cash reserve to make any of the following magical technologies a reality but it didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /nine-magical-features-left-out-of-the-iphone-5</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/nine-magical-features-left-out-of-the-iphone-5</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>API First Fruits: Scripting &amp; Automation for the Masses</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The API economy is in full force. Businesses and startups large and small are providing data and processing programmatically. APIs have rapidly become key structures in business and revenue models.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /api-first-fruits-scripting-automation-for-the</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/api-first-fruits-scripting-automation-for-the</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Personal Software Agents In An Information Economy</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The basic principle of an information economy is that the individuals who can perform the most efficient, creative, and useful transformations on data make the most money. Thats an over simplification but it still gets at the heart of the matter. Well what happens when the tools of information processing become dramatically more powerful? Productivity and value explode. Today, a teenager with a $200 tablet computer can process information with greater efficiency than an entire organization of fifty years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /personal-software-agents-in-an-information-economy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/personal-software-agents-in-an-information-economy</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Fiddle World: Online Development Sandboxes</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Several development sandboxes have popped up online in the last year that are well worth your time to check out. Dev sandboxes allow for bug isolation, test driving new libraries, sharing programming problems, and saving solutions for later referral. These are the top four.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /a-fiddle-world-online-development-sandboxes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/a-fiddle-world-online-development-sandboxes</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Digital Dominance: Learn to code. Now.</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to thrive in the exploding information economy of the 21st Century, it is essential that you learn to understand, write, and think in code.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /digital-dominance-learn-to-code-now</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/digital-dominance-learn-to-code-now</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Augmented Reality: Living in Cyberspace</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The evolution of human/machine interface will travel through several definable epochs. Each epoch does not make the previous obsolete but does drastically alter and improve the efficiency and ease of our interaction with technology and information.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /augmented-reality-living-in-cyberspace</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/augmented-reality-living-in-cyberspace</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The BlackBerry PlayBook Doesn’t Exist</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I am truly shocked that so many people are being duped by BlackBerry’s recent announcement of their tablet, the PlayBook. I have read endless comments from people who are saying they can’t wait to get this tablet computer. Well, I think I have some bad news for you folks.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-blackberry-playbook-doesnt-exist</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-blackberry-playbook-doesnt-exist</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
