<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/bitcoin/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2022-01-18T06:47:47+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/bitcoin/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Singularity Hacker | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Singularity Hacker</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Front-Running Defi Regulation</title>
      <link href="/front-running-defi-regulation" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Front-Running Defi Regulation" />
      <published>2021-04-19T10:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-04-19T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/front-running-defi-regulation</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/front-running-defi-regulation">&lt;p&gt;Last week was big for crypto. The Coinbase IPO happened and the whole world seemed to wake up in recognition of crypto as an asset class. While this is a major step in the legitimization of the space, some even calling it crypto’s ’&lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://cointelegraph.com/news/coinbase-listing-is-crypto-s-netscape-moment-says-mike-novogratz&quot;&gt;Netscape moment&lt;/a&gt;’, I want to take the opportunity to highlight the dangers of crypto going mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United States is woefully behind in the crypto economy in every conceivable measure. For Bitcoin PoW blockchain, the U.S. represents a mere &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.statista.com/statistics/1200477/bitcoin-mining-by-country/&quot;&gt;7%&lt;/a&gt; of the global hash rate while China represents approx. 65%. This has lead thinkers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-07/peter-thiel-calls-bitcoin-a-chinese-financial-weapon-at-virtual-roundtable&quot;&gt;Peter Thiel&lt;/a&gt; to suggest that Bitcoin could in fact be a Chinese financial weapon against the U.S. and to unambiguously state that it specifically threatens the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the U.S. government is frighteningly slow to even understand what crypto is or what it has produced in decentralized finance (Defi). This is clearly seen in the recent Bankless &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gd84ALWwpRQ&amp;amp;ab_channel=Bankless&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with SEC commission Hester Peirce when she talks about Defi barely being on the radar of her fellow commissioners and that they are just now waking up to Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the U.S. is &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.marketwatch.com/story/u-s-is-behind-the-curve-on-crypto-regulations-says-sec-commissioner-peirce-11617824160&quot;&gt;behind the curve on crypto regulation&lt;/a&gt;. If you spent any time in the space you will be familiar with popups at every turn telling you that U.S. customers are not able to use this exchange or Defi product due to regulatory restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“BitMEX, Bybit, FTX and Binance are four of the top coveted exchanges that ban U.S. persons from their platform, as stated in their terms and conditions… Kraken even has a separate futures trading platform, which oddly, U.S. customers are barred from using.” - &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.forbes.com/sites/benjaminpirus/2020/09/30/crypto-exchanges-barring-us-citizens-is-heartbreaking-and-frustrating/?sh=41b452ef7c97&quot;&gt;Crypto Exchanges Barring US Citizens Is Heartbreaking And Frustrating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given this deficit in understanding and an anticipated growing sense of diminished control, I fear any major market downswing could trigger sweeping regulation. Many people are predicting crypto regulation on the horizon regardless of any downturn. The World Economic Forum’s head of blockchain and digital assets, Sheila Warren, just told Bloomberg that a “dramatic” round of regulation was about to befall Bitcoin and the wider cryptocurrency space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re going to see another round of pretty dramatic attempts at regulating this space. As there’s more and more activity in these spaces there’s more and more demand signal for regulators to get engaged and involved.” - &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://cointelegraph.com/news/there-will-be-drama-warns-wef-expert-on-bitcoin-regulation&quot;&gt;Cointelegraph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writing on the wall seems to be exceedingly clear and it indicates that &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://modernconsensus.com/regulation/the-feds-are-coming-for-defi/&quot;&gt;the feds are coming for Defi&lt;/a&gt;. Combined with the US having printed 40% of its money supply just last year potentially conducting &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPW1tbMOAA4&amp;amp;ab_channel=MHFIN&quot;&gt;the scariest financial experiment in history&lt;/a&gt;, Defi has the potential to be an enticing scapegoat to any undesirable economic consequences. The heavy-handed regulation will be presented as being for our own good and motivated to “protect” citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what people need to fully understand and take in is that Defi is not merely an augmentation to traditional finance, it’s a repudiation of it. It’s a Wikipedia to Britannica, an Amazon to Borders, and a Netflix to Blockbuster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does knowing any of this help you? As a blockchain developer/user, you can prioritize the following protocol characteristics to stay ahead of the idiocracy soon to flow from governments desperate to maintain control of your economic life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Availability&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the front end of your application is hosted on AWS  and your domain is registered with GoDaddy then your decentralized and censorship-resistant submarine might as well have a screen door on it. To guarantee availability to end-users means employing censorship-resistant technologies like IPFS and ENS.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Governance&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make no mistake about it. when the regulatory guns come out, they will be squarely targeted at At those who are building and managing these products, and if you are in a position where you can update protocols then you will be legally compelled to do so. A trustless system is not trustless if the founders have to be trusted to not update the protocol at the behest of another. This means on-chain governance.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Anonymity&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Even assuming that there is no attack vector at the protocol level, this does not mean that the blockchain creators are safe from attack by governments. If their identity is known, they are fully exposed to the threat of personal liability. This could mean their personal assets are confiscated or they’re held criminally liable for building and releasing the product. Just ask &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.coindesk.com/former-bitmex-ceo-hayes-surrenders-to-face-us-charges-report&quot;&gt;Arthur Hayes&lt;/a&gt;. I believe anonymity will be shown to be as important for founders as it has been emphasized as a feature for users.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;PoS Consensus&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We need to move away from Proof of Work (PoW) to Proof of Stake (PoS) as soon as possible and it’s not just about scalability and speed of transactions. Physical mining represents a very real physical vulnerability because governments can dramatically lower the cost of a 51% attack simply by seizing control of the mining physical infrastructure required to drive PoW. That dramatically changes in the move to PoS because there is no physical infrastructure per se. What’s more, it also increases anonymity by removing miner IP addresses from the equation and provides greater resiliency in the face of &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://cointelegraph.com/news/did-a-massive-chinese-power-outage-cause-bitcoin-s-crash-down-to-50k&quot;&gt;power loss&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building the decentralized trustless system requires a constant obsession with thinking about how users can be attacked and exploited. The same passion that exists behind decentralization will exist on the side of governments who wish to control and exploit it for power. This conflict is unprecedented for several reasons. Firstly, the servers running the code do not reside in any physical country and, secondly, all parties involved are involved voluntarily so it can’t be construed as an issue of theft or exploitation. These reasons alone will inevitably cause people to rightly question what grounds a government has to control this space but, I’m convinced, that will not deter them from claiming that right. The only way to front-run the impending clash of worldviews is with the same principles that have driven this entire movement, that being an absolute insistence on unmitigated trustlessness and decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the very interesting projects I see taking the above characteristics extremely seriously is &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.dfohub.com/&quot;&gt;DFOhub&lt;/a&gt;. They advocate the use of decentralized flexible organizations (DFOs) and speak of &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YU_wD_Cnvz4&amp;amp;ab_channel=DFOhub&quot;&gt;startups without founders&lt;/a&gt;. I personally feel that they’re extremely ahead of the curve and that time will show the great value of the thinkers and projects exploring and expanding the boundaries of this space.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Singularity Hacker</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="blockchain" />
      
        <category term="defi" />
      
        <category term="ethereum" />
      
        <category term="crypto" />
      
        <category term="regulatio" />
      
        <category term="bitcoin" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Last week was big for crypto. The Coinbase IPO happened and the whole world seemed to wake up in recognition of crypto as an asset class. While this is a major step in the legitimization of the space, some even calling it crypto’s ’Netscape moment’, I want to take the opportunity to highlight the dangers of crypto going mainstream.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Is Blockchain a Fad?</title>
      <link href="/is-blockchain-a-fad" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is Blockchain a Fad?" />
      <published>2021-03-20T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-03-20T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/is-blockchain-a-fad</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/is-blockchain-a-fad">&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is the technology on which Bitcoin and all other cryptocurrencies are built. Much of the talk around this technology revolves around speculation and making fast money. Because of this many scams have been pulled and this has, in turn, led many people to discount the entire technology as unnecessary and as even a scam itself. In fact, my favorite place for tech news for over a decade has been Hacker News but you will find nearly all the comments on all articles related to blockchain technology completely dismissive of it. It was pretty shocking to me when I first saw it because the level of disdain for anything related to blockchain technology on Hacker News is nearly absolute. There aren’t even metered assessments such as Blockchain has a specific and limited use case but rather the opinions are that the technology has zero use and has zero value in any context. One can’t help but give pause and really wonder if you’re being deceived when the likes of Bill Gates and Warren Buffett dismiss the entire technology as worthless as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think twice before you listen to advice from people who don’t know the difference between Bitcoin and Blockchain. You might as well take technology advice from someone who doesn’t know the difference between Facebook and the World Wide Web. For as many naysayers, there are thought leaders who pronounce Blockchain as his greatest discovery of man since fire, the wheel, and the internet. Steve Wozniak for one compares it to the early days of Apple when they were still in the garage. The very fact that these disagreements and controversies exist points to the reality of how early we are in the development and application of this technology. The polarization is so deep right now you could almost say that the mental divide that existed between the pre-internet mindsets and the pioneers of the internet now exists between traditional internet thinkers and decentralized Blockchain thinkers. Time will show you who the truly prescient ones were. Consider the following analogy that illustrates where I think we are with this technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine we’re in the early nineteen hundreds and there are only 100,000 cars in the country. By 1908 there will be somewhere around 200,000 vehicles registered in the United States and around 500 companies busily making more types of cars. Ford leads the pack with the Model T, Buick is right behind them, and General Motors has just been founded and will be creating even more models. There are no shortage of critics. The president of a Michigan savings bank advised Horace Rackham, Henry Ford’s lawyer, not to invest in his client’s company, telling him, “The horse is here to stay, but the automobile is only a novelty – a fad.” The Washington Post stated that “Local horse dealers do not look upon the advent of the automobile with any degree of seriousness. It is true that society has taken up the automobile, but the dealers consider it nothing but a fad, which will not have as much permanency as the bicycle. They argue that the noise of the engine or motor will soon wear the tender nerves of the society belle or swell to a frazzle and that the odor of the locomobile is not at all agreeable to the sensitive nostrils.” - &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; from May 14th, 1900&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the following parallels. Blockchain is to the crypto ecosystem what the internal combustion engine was to the automobile ecosystem. Bitcoin is the Model T of this new burgeoning ecosystem. It has all the brand recognition and it’s come to be almost entirely identified with the automobile itself. But there are many other types of automobiles on the road and many more will come that bring their own unique properties, strengths, and weaknesses. There are numerous other cryptocurrencies and Blockchains that exist besides Bitcoin. There were many unorthodox car designs in the early days and even foolish applications of the internal combustion engine but none of these discounted the entire revolution in transportation that was transpiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like the analogy with these cars, there doesn’t need to be one car to rule them all or a “winner”. Each protocol can have its own unique properties suited to a specific use case. One doesn’t even need to know which particular car is going to do well or not in the market. Just knowing that the world is going to be overtaken by cars as a product category puts you in an extremely advantageous position. Certainly better than the horse traders who could see nothing but another fad. A person with this knowledge can invest in cars at the ecosystem level. As I’ve stated elsewhere, this technology has produced digital scarcity, something inconceivable prior to the Bitcoin whitepaper and we are in the very early stages of recognizing its impact and potential applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two methods of analysis that are used when analyzing the value of any asset security. Technical analysis and fundamental analysis. Technical analysis has to do with understanding charts and the fluctuating price of something and trying to infer certain patterns to determine whether the price will go up or down. This is what a lot of people think of when they think of cryptocurrency and Blockchain. This involves studying charts and buying tokens when they’re cheap and waiting for them to go up in value and making lots of money. But fundamental analysis has to do with the intrinsic utility of the thing being studied. That is, regardless of how the price is fluctuating or what the current demand is, how useful is this thing? This is what separates the traders and investors. So drawing upon the previous analogy with the history of automobiles, I asked myself, what is the fundamental utility of programmable digital scarcity? This technology not only has the power to displace everything we’ve known concerning financial systems but it also has the potential to completely rewrite the internet and all digital coordination as we have known it thus far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-img.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Singularity Hacker</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="blockchain" />
      
        <category term="bitcoin" />
      
        <category term="cryptocurrency" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Blockchain is the technology on which Bitcoin and all other cryptocurrencies are built. Much of the talk around this technology revolves around speculation and making fast money. Because of this many scams have been pulled and this has, in turn, led many people to discount the entire technology as unnecessary and as even a scam itself. In fact, my favorite place for tech news for over a decade has been Hacker News but you will find nearly all the comments on all articles related to blockchain technology completely dismissive of it. It was pretty shocking to me when I first saw it because the level of disdain for anything related to blockchain technology on Hacker News is nearly absolute. There aren’t even metered assessments such as Blockchain has a specific and limited use case but rather the opinions are that the technology has zero use and has zero value in any context. One can’t help but give pause and really wonder if you’re being deceived when the likes of Bill Gates and Warren Buffett dismiss the entire technology as worthless as well.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">CombatOps: Running Wars from a Keyboard</title>
      <link href="/combatops" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=" CombatOps: Running Wars from a Keyboard " />
      <published>2014-10-14T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2014-10-14T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/combatops</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/combatops">&lt;p&gt;There’s no free lunch. Every strength has a cost. The same technologies that enable distributed anonymous communication enable terrorist organizations to communicate unimpeded. Or the same advances in additive manufacturing make it possible to print firearms from the comfort of your bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This creates a genuine dilemma for nation states trying to enforce the rule of law in a technological singularity. It is, today, possible to start a full blown war from a keyboard.. full stop. I want to talk about three mechanisms that are being leveraged to do that very thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication: Who needs dead drops and burner phones when you have distributed social networks. Enter Diaspora. Diaspora came about because people didn’t want Facebook to own their data. Diaspora operates on a node/pod basis such that each pod is autonomous and shares its users info with other pods. Any one can fork the Diaspora code and fire up a pod on any server. Instant scalable social network. Strangely enough, it’s the primary means the terrorist group &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/aug/21/islamic-state-isis-social-media-diaspora-twitter-clampdown&quot;&gt;ISIS is using to communicate now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funding: Money laundering is so old-timey. With Bitcoin, or any altcoin for that matter, even high profile figures can funnel unlimited funds to special interest groups anonymously. It effectively becomes possible to crowdsource military operations from a keyboard from within the state you are waging war against using it’s own economy and citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armaments: Arms dealing is dead. &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.wired.com/2014/05/3d-printed-guns/&quot;&gt;3D printed firearms have disrupted the scene&lt;/a&gt;. Printed firearms are undetectable and untraceable and can be assembled on a just-in-time bases. And it’s not just firearms any more. &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.wired.com/2014/09/military-grade-drone-can-printed-anywhere/&quot;&gt;Printed drones are becoming a thing&lt;/a&gt;. I’m envisioning a future where you can have a war kit in a suitcase. Open it up and guns and a cloud of drones fly out. Yesterdays crockpot bomb is tomorrows printed nuke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least we have advances in Intelligent Systems. The concept of a DAC (Distributed Autonomous Corporations) can and is being applied to combatant endeavors in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.forbes.com/sites/andygreenberg/2013/11/18/meet-the-assassination-market-creator-whos-crowdfunding-murder-with-bitcoins/&quot;&gt;assassination markets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combat DACs can be disastrous to standard counter terrorism techniques which rely on social network analysis (SNA) to ferret out cells and cell  members. Using a DAC would mean there’s no critical communication between cell groups or cell members  and that no single operative has enough knowledge to compromise the operation. Each player would be independently directed by the DAC to achieve the overarching mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-img-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t seen Balaji Srinivasan’s talk on &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cOubCHLXT6A&quot;&gt;Silicon Valley’s Ultimate Exit&lt;/a&gt; then watch it now. What he describes is an opting out of nation-state citizenship on a technological and economic level. The idea is that you could have cyber nations on top of “real” ones. The interesting part about the above observations is that it’s not only possible to opt out in the Srinivasan fashion but also possible for these cyber nations to wage war against the meatspace nations they inhabit and to, there by, assert their own sovereignty.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Singularity Hacker</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="cyberwar" />
      
        <category term="bitcoin" />
      
        <category term="3dprinter" />
      
        <category term="diaspora" />
      
        <category term="singularity" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">There’s no free lunch. Every strength has a cost. The same technologies that enable distributed anonymous communication enable terrorist organizations to communicate unimpeded. Or the same advances in additive manufacturing make it possible to print firearms from the comfort of your bedroom.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">The Bitbay</title>
      <link href="/the-bitbay" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Bitbay" />
      <published>2014-06-13T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2014-06-13T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/the-bitbay</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/the-bitbay">&lt;p&gt;The Pirate Bay is the most famous fire sharing brand in the world. It wasn’t always that way (remember Napster) and it wont be that way for much longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;File sharing technology has evolved over the years and, with each iteration, has increasingly immunized it’s self from the threat of seizure and shut down. The next generation of P2P technology has just arrived in the form of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.wired.com/2014/04/darkmarket/&quot;&gt;DarkMarket&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.forbes.com/sites/andygreenberg/2013/10/31/darkwallet-aims-to-be-the-anarchists-bitcoin-app-of-choice/&quot;&gt;Dark Wallet&lt;/a&gt;. The technology now exist to run a fully distributed and anonymous marketplace impervious to any attempts to shut it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology may have arrived but the next great file sharing brand has not. I think that The Bit Bay could be that brand. It springboards off the brand recognition of The Pirate Bay and yet, would be built on a surer technological foundation. I’v been speculating that Bitcoin could be a means of monetizing file sharing for some time and I still think that the first person to execute on this idea will be stacking more benjamins then Kim Dotcom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fews years ago, I developed a prototype demonstrating the concept. This prototype has no backend because something like DarkMarket didn’t exist yet but it does use a Java applet from &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.bitlet.org/&quot;&gt;bitlet.org&lt;/a&gt; that enables users to download torrent files without installing a client. All the code is inline so it could be posted to a paste bin or an anonymous static-file host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog07.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m giving away this blackhat startup idea in hopes that someone with more savvy than I will run with it. Do amazing things!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m selling &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fauctions.godaddy.com%2FtrpItemListing.aspx%3F%26miid%3D137160013&amp;amp;t=NjhiNTRkMjFkMWNjOWFiMDRiYTViNWFjMDdhNjdhZDU5OGY0MjlmMSxIcFhUNmV3Mg%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3Amc9oE5TJkAXO_RNMdoK8vQ&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fsingularityhacker.com%2Fpost%2F85648826500%2Fthe-bitbay&amp;amp;m=1&amp;amp;ts=1642047023&quot;&gt;thebitbay.com&lt;/a&gt; domain for a very reasonable rate and my website prototype on &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://gumroad.com/l/HaUaw&quot;&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt; for $5. Happy hacking!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Singularity Hacker</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="bitcoin" />
      
        <category term="piracy" />
      
        <category term="darkmarket" />
      
        <category term="darkwallet" />
      
        <category term="piratebay" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">The Pirate Bay is the most famous fire sharing brand in the world. It wasn’t always that way (remember Napster) and it wont be that way for much longer.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
