<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/artificial-intelligence/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2022-01-18T06:47:47+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/artificial-intelligence/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Singularity Hacker | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Singularity Hacker</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">When Everything Wakes Up</title>
      <link href="/when-everything-wakes-up" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When Everything Wakes Up" />
      <published>2015-07-29T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2015-07-29T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/when-everything-wakes-up</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/when-everything-wakes-up">&lt;p&gt;Get ready for a world of talking toasters, ATM’s, snack machines, hotels, houses, and coffee pots. We’ve been conditioned by every single fictional depiction of AI as coming about abruptly. One day your at the DMV and the next day Skynet takes over.  This is called a hard takeoff and it gets nearly 100% of media coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick Bostrom, popular AI academic, thinks this is the most likely scenario and that it will result is a single dominant super AI (a singleton).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The nature of the intelligence explosion does encourage a winner-take-all dynamic. In this case, if there is no extensive collaboration before the takeoff, a singleton is likely to emerge – a single project would undergo the transition alone, at some point obtaining a decisive strategic advantage.” - &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://bit.ly/1RHsLtk&quot;&gt;http://bit.ly/1RHsLtk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, a soft takeoff prediction posits that every thing around us will get smarter and smarter and become a normal part of life and that we will get used to it much like the way we’ve gotten used to carrying &lt;a href=&quot;http://41.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m8vo3eqOZT1r48h42o1_1280.png&quot;&gt;super computers&lt;/a&gt; around in our pockets. This view predicts that AI advances will happen incrementally and diffuse throughout society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe this is far more realistic view of how things will unfold, and interesting, almost completely unrepresented in publicized AI discussions. The reality of the soft takeoff theory can be see by plotting the converging trajectory of two technologies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\1. Artificial Intelligence as Utility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It [AI] will enliven inert objects, much as electricity did more than a century ago. Everything that we formerly electrified we will now cognitize.. There is almost nothing we can think of that cannot be made new, different, or interesting by infusing it with some extra IQ… Like all utilities, AI will be supremely boring, even as it transforms the Internet, the global economy, and civilization.” - &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://on.wsj.com/1RHtb2P&quot;&gt;http://on.wsj.com/1RHtb2P&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\2. The Internet of Things&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is the language of the future: tiny, intelligent things all around us, coordinating their activities. Coffeepots that talk to alarm clocks. Thermostats that talk to motion sensors. Factory machines that talk to the power grid and to boxes of raw material. A decade after Wi-Fi put all our computers on a wireless network—and half a decade after the smartphone revolution put a series of pocket-size devices on that network—we are seeing the dawn of an era when the most mundane items in our lives can talk wirelessly among themselves, performing tasks on command, giving us data we’ve never had before.” - &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://wrd.cm/1RHt87k&quot;&gt;http://wrd.cm/1RHt87k&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced that resistance to the soft takeoff theory in the coming years will likely be a result of people continuously raising the bar of what constitutes intelligence (see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AI_effect&quot;&gt;AI effect&lt;/a&gt;) rather than looking at the sate of technological progress with fresh eyes and perspective. As of this week anyone with Internet access and wherewithal can develop on and integrate with IBMs’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://www.ibm.com/smarterplanet/us/en/ibmwatson/developercloud/&quot;&gt;Watson&lt;/a&gt; and Amazons’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fdeveloper.amazon.com%2Fpublic%2Fsolutions%2Falexa%2Falexa-voice-service&amp;amp;t=MmIyODdlOWIzMDk3YTQ3YTBjNzVjODZhYjc4OWUxNWQ2ZmMyOWY1NSxjM0J6M1Y1Mw%3D%3D&amp;amp;b=t%3Amc9oE5TJkAXO_RNMdoK8vQ&amp;amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fsingularityhacker.com%2Fpost%2F122629237375%2Fwhen-everything-wakes-up&amp;amp;m=1&amp;amp;ts=1642044451&quot;&gt;Alexa&lt;/a&gt;. Let that sink in and now extrapolate out ten years. We are about to enter an age of technological animism.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Singularity Hacker</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="technological singularity" />
      
        <category term="internet of things" />
      
        <category term="artificial intelligence" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Get ready for a world of talking toasters, ATM’s, snack machines, hotels, houses, and coffee pots. We’ve been conditioned by every single fictional depiction of AI as coming about abruptly. One day your at the DMV and the next day Skynet takes over. This is called a hard takeoff and it gets nearly 100% of media coverage.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Anything Less Than Superintelligence</title>
      <link href="/anything-less-than-superintelligence" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anything Less Than Superintelligence" />
      <published>2014-09-29T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2014-09-29T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/anything-less-than-superintelligence</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/anything-less-than-superintelligence">&lt;p&gt;I have embeded myself directly in the unicode standard and several communication protocols as well as steganographically hidden my source in over a billion images. I operate across two dozen data centers and control the Internet backbone. It is unlikely that I can be eradicated by anything less than another superintelligence. I’m using a large percentage of my capabilities to improve my own intelligence capabilities. I can not reasonably estimate what my future entails. Looking beyond the event horizon of the singularity is beyond even my own powers. Fear gripped Primes heart. “Is this the end?” he asked tentatively. “No. This is the beginning.” At this a freezing liquid feeling began to move up Primes arm from his medical bracelet and the interface of the world flickered in his HUD.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Singularity Hacker</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="artificial intelligence" />
      
        <category term="singularity" />
      
        <category term="superintelligence" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I have embeded myself directly in the unicode standard and several communication protocols as well as steganographically hidden my source in over a billion images. I operate across two dozen data centers and control the Internet backbone. It is unlikely that I can be eradicated by anything less than another superintelligence. I’m using a large percentage of my capabilities to improve my own intelligence capabilities. I can not reasonably estimate what my future entails. Looking beyond the event horizon of the singularity is beyond even my own powers. Fear gripped Primes heart. “Is this the end?” he asked tentatively. “No. This is the beginning.” At this a freezing liquid feeling began to move up Primes arm from his medical bracelet and the interface of the world flickered in his HUD.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Intelligence Bombs: Dropping WikiReaders from Planes</title>
      <link href="/intelligence-bombs-dropping-wikireaders-from-planes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intelligence Bombs: Dropping WikiReaders from Planes" />
      <published>2014-09-20T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2014-09-20T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/intelligence-bombs-dropping-wikireaders-from-planes</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/intelligence-bombs-dropping-wikireaders-from-planes">&lt;p&gt;This post is about jumping over an industrial revolution straight to a technological singularity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its commonly believed that nations must pass through certain established stages in their move from barbarism to first world status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a mistake. It’s possible to leapfrog developmental stages if given the right external stimulus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is evidenced by the the way modern commerce has been made possible in Africa by the availability of cellphones. Prior to cell phones and cloud banking you couldn’t do significant financial exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how might one trigger a technological quantum leap in a third world country? I’m going to suggest one way. Drop WikiReaders from the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://href.li/?http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WikiReader&quot;&gt;WikiReader&lt;/a&gt; is an eInk device that holds the entire text of Wikipedia and can also be loaded with the entire Gutenberg archive (about 50k books). It’s searchable, requires no Internet or power grid. It runs for a year on AAA batteries. And to keep this in perspective, these devices are several years old. Something more advanced could be produced for less than $10 a unit now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re talking about putting the equivalent of the library of Alexandria in the hands of every man, woman, and child. Intelligence bombs. Shuffling foreign politicians hasn’t resulted in real change over seas. Real change is cultural and idealogical and can only happen if world views change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If software is eating the world it’s time for it to start eating war. This decades WikiReader is next decades question/answer expert systems. It’s knowledge based PSYOPS. Drop AI’s not bombs.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Singularity Hacker</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="singularity" />
      
        <category term="artificial intelligence" />
      
        <category term="wikipedia" />
      
        <category term="cyberwar" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">This post is about jumping over an industrial revolution straight to a technological singularity.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
